Rikuto! Look!
You can see it!
The island your dad used to live on!
Huh?
First time this far out
in the sticks, huh?
But forget all that,
look how big you’ve gotten!
I grew five centimeters last year!
Attaboy!
Well then...
Rikuto-chan, you go play your heart out
in the outdoors!
Leafia, can I leave Rikuto
in your care?
Rikuto! You said you wanted
to see a Koratta, right?
Huh? There’s a Koratta here?!
The Pokemon ‘round here
all get along real well with us folks,
so you might just
make some new friends!
Thanks for the treat!
Leafia! C’mon, quick!
Be back for dinner, you hear?
I’m heading out!
Now, then. We oughta get the feast ready.
Let’s hop to it, yeah?
Uh... Let’s hop to it, yeah.
Where could it be?
Where’s the Koratta?
There it is!
Whoa, hold up!
Ow... Ow, ow...
Huh?
It’s a Kameil!
I’ve never seen one before!
You two know each other?
Huh?
This Kameil... Isn’t its tail a sorta
different color from what’s in the Index?
There’s moss growing on its shell, too...
Huh! When a Kameil lives
for a long time, its tail changes color!
Sorry, I didn’t really think
before grabbing—
Hold up!
How far are you gonna go?!
Kameil!
Wait...
Just hol—
Uh... Wh... What?
Is this a slide?
“Come on down!”?
Eugh, no way, no way, no way!
Huh?
Leafia, will you go with me?
Here we go. Ready, and...!
That’s payback for earlier!
Rikuto!
Hey!
How far did he go, playing around?
Huh?
Rikuto!
Ah! Dad!
How did you get
all the way down there...?
Huh?
Is that...?
Dad, you come down here too!
No, no, no,
I couldn’t slide down this at my age...
That’s cold!
Huh?
Huh? Kameil?!
Just hol— Waaaah!
So you... really are
the Kameil from back th—
Yay! He got Dad, too!
Ahh! Kameil, don’t run away!
You’re in for it!
Hey!
Don’t even think about...
...leaving me out of the fun!
Let me join in!
Ahh... I’m exhausted...
Heh, what a joke...
Oh, right. Rikuto-chan.
Huh?
Give this to Kameil.
To Kameil?
It’s adooored them since forever!
Here!
You’re friends with Kameil too,
Grandma?
There was a biiig tunnel
in the forest, right?
That’s a shortcut I made
waaay back with Kameil!
I went through that!
Then, what about that slide?
He made that with me.
What?!
Oh!
I think it was...
somewhere around here...
Ahh, here! Here it is!
What is it?
I buried this thirty years ago
with Kameil!
This really takes me back!
Ooh! This is you
when you were young?
And this Eevee...?
Leafia, when he was young.
Wow!
But you haven’t changed at all, Kameil!
Well, they do say Kameil live for
‘round ten thousand years!
So you’re a really old geezer?
Or maybe he’s still just a child.
Well, it makes no difference
how old he is!
When we all play together,
we can always
go back to this summer.
You there! A battle!
What a weird face!
I came back for more fun!
It’s finished!
Kameil, look, look! A rainbow!
Hold up, Kameil!
Let’s go, Kameil!
Kameil!
Now, then...
Should we start heading back?
Your mom says she’s almost here.
Really? Then Kameil,
you can join us at—
Huh?
Kameil?
Kameil, where’d you go?
Oh, right... Even back then, he had a habit of
disappearing before you knew it...
Will I ever see him again?
I’ll make sure!
I’ll come back next year!
So when I do...
Let’s play together again, Kameil!